{"qu1":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>5<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>To complete a certain job, P, working alone, takes twice as long as Q and R together take, whereas Q, working alone, takes 11 times as long as P and R together take. If all the three of them together can complete the job in four days, find the time taken by Q, working alone, to complete the job.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>24\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>36\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>48\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>64\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"c","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu2":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>5<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>The set S<sub>x<\/sub> is defined as (<i>x<\/i>, <i>x<\/i> + 1, <i>x<\/i> + 2, <i>x<\/i> + 3, <i>x<\/i> + 4), for <i>x<\/i> = 1, 2, 3. . . . . .  50. How many of these sets contain a multiple of five or a multiple of seven but not both?\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>15\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>14\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>13\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>12\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"a","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu3":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>5<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Farooq purchases two watermelons, one weighing 20% more than the other. However, due to the summer heat, the combined weight of the two watermelons reduces by one-fourth. If the weight of the heavier watermelon reduces to 75% of its initial weight, then the lighter watermelon incurs a weight loss of\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>20%.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>25%.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>5%.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>22.5%.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"b","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu4":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>5<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>A vessel contains 20 litres of pure alcohol. Five litres of the alcohol is first replaced with water and then four litres of the diluted alcohol is again replaced with water. What is the ratio of alcohol and water in the vessel now?\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>7 : 5\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>5 : 4\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>4 : 3\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>3 : 2\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"d","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu5":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>5<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>The ratio of the number of chocolates with A and B is 3 : 4. If A gives four chocolates to B, then the ratio of the number of chocolates with A and B will become 1 : 2. Find the total number of chocolates with them.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>70\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>56\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>42\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>126\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"c","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu6":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i> <\/i><i>6<\/i><i>:<\/i> Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Sirisha deposits four amounts, that are in the ratio 3 : 2 : 5 : 4, in four banks, P, Q, R, S, respectively. If the interest rates offered by P, Q, R, S are 5%, 5.5%, 8% and 7% per annum respectively, and the total interest accrued after one year is Rs.94000, find the interest (in Rs.) obtained from bank R.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"40000","CORRECT_ANSWER":"40000","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu7":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\"><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>7<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>1<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">log<sub>3<\/sub><sub>6<\/sub> (8<i>x<\/i> + 5) &lt; log<sub>6<\/sub><sub> <\/sub><i>x<\/i> + log<sub>6<\/sub><sub> <\/sub>2, if and only if <i>x<\/i> &gt; <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<img alt=\"\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,R0lGODlhGQAtAPcAAP\/\/\/\/+2ZgAAAAAAOpDb\/\/\/bkDoAOgAAZrb\/\/\/\/\/tmYAOtuQOgA6kNv\/\/zoAADo6kP\/\/25A6AGa2\/2YAALZmAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAACwAAAAAGQAtAAAIiwABCBxIsKDBgwgTKlzIsKHDhxAjSpxIsaLFgQEECBhAYGIBAx0DHEBgMYGCjhUXMGhAsYADjhdFkqxoEiXFmhJlAijwgKXEBRpHXhxKtKhRiRqTKhVwlCiECBIWutQYVWKCCVEDwIwYYCWAp1VvYrWo0ufEBUIpLth6Nq1HkBYpLA3btK7du3jrBgQAOw==\" style=\"width: 25px; height: 45px;\" \/><\/p>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>2.\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<p>\r\n\t<img alt=\"\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,R0lGODlhFgAmAPcAAP\/\/\/9uQOgAAAAAAZrb\/\/7ZmAGa2\/\/\/\/25A6OpDb\/\/\/\/tmYAAP\/bkDoAOv+2ZgA6kNv\/\/5A6ZgAAOpA6ADoAAGYAOgBmtjqQ2wAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAACwAAAAAFgAmAAAIgwABCBxIsKDBgwgTKlzIsKFDhgEESBxA4CGAAgYsDjyAIIFGgQoWSBSQ8SGDBh45evx4seRHjA8dPIAA4ECEig8jCpCwkqXPn0CDfhxJVIBQoAcmuDxakAEFiUsZKqjg8WRPhg4sDIT5cepVh0kvdF0gVqPTqA3PstQ5Ei3Tt3DjHg0IADs=\" style=\"width: 22px; height: 38px;\" \/><\/p>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>3.\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"c","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu8":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\"><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>7<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>1<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<img alt=\"\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,R0lGODlhzQIiAPcAAP\/\/\/wAAAP\/\/25A6AGa2\/\/\/bkDoAOpDb\/zoAZrb\/\/7ZmAAA6kNvbkDoAAAAAOgAAZtv\/\/\/\/\/tmYAANuQOv+2ZmYAOjqQ2wA6ZmY6ADpmZjo6OtuQkDo6kJA6OrbbkJCQOjqQkDo6ZmYAZrb\/tmaQkABmtjo6AJDbtraQOrZmOpC2kLb\/25A6Ztu2Zjpmtma227ZmZgAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAACwAAAAAzQIiAAAI\/wABCBxIsKDBgwgTKlzIsKHDhxAjSpxIsaLFixgzatzIsaPHjyBDihxJsqTJkyhTqlzJsqXLlzBjypxJs6bNmzhz6tzJs6fPn0CDCh1KtKjRo0iTKl3KtKnTp1CjSp1KtarVq1izLgzAtatXr1rDih1LtqxZmgHOql3Ltq3btxDTwp1Lt67du0vl4t3Lt69fu18DdwWpt6hgwX9tHkacuLFjsoUfS55MuXLdyJYza97MOapeAQMIGCxg4EDn0w9Jm06NIMHFAq03KgiwgEHskAUaeHVwIPdX3gNhu84q3GJxhcclJgew3KXvAA+GI1QtcPYCCAUjSPgqeoJg0Q0pcP8FnlAu6ADgB4Im3zJChdUEtXMHIL9r9Ifeud4\/H8BCSOu2SZeQe\/AV1Bxyt2F0IEPWYRffdl6lB4B3EkJE3UIEMpdgTBeS1OEE9zFX2kcZklTiQCcqlOGCHbH40IobZpRieOgJRAF7o43Y4YPp3Qjfjgxp112IBsnl3QUYVDhBBiO6NCN9EvTIm5ADKXCdQwpUaCUEQGrUpYrvxRemi6PFGBGMAjb0JZU2kqedBlcq1ySYppGpkp0bdcjmlxg9SWKYYhY44JhmeoQnhoSm2SegDoEm4QRx5lhnoWwCAJp\/AvGJEAX3+QmAXBsk4ChBBXDAwJwsPVnppZVyquhBAnQZUKCneRY66KyJsvbqi7laSGmU6g2AKaceoP+aWmmwfcAVpihux1uyXIF3HpEEzRYACO8JpwCmGU7rGrT9GagbesdZi21vsQlXQAgYoOdtQnoC2mVxz1UIgHjLPhgAcPiGCy6z5ob57r\/ysVewafxFCuW+6Cpbo6UDQKdoff6pyy56FGvo2rsohkllBCJ4gMAIzjYcrUEZQyyxhg5bcPC67RLAcXAb8qlavSgDK9ComaLaL1cKUwmpg0USxLOlsq4JoX+gkaBbCfiWYFC\/FSPQcpVcnZtzeo5WmqWNXwVdgQkMazzg0hA7HQDUXEk93bgEqGt1vtVlzejLcz88c6axDZw3wHafUDK49iaMHc7Z6QwxeNteOtHNDfj\/52p2Y0Z+730KSD2B2wQNDYACz7ZGwZWjY5f5hFLnJjm1ZhfnOejoftua6tVpzrmkA3kuoqAax2pa6TxeLmCGVLpK++SvA3f65sxZ7uqM3Q4gNWi301f56q4tX73jQqprOfdRFqd9Qdveq4HkJQi3ovPUgi\/a+MdHtz6m4xMEfLP29jzpq62ypylC8lHYp+RSmKNNoGLGgph\/hASa62jHgYyCkmiMx77suQ12WxuIj+rTFWYthDogSsDoUHAyowlLgg2EwANVGEEDpWt2FfzcBXE0P+HJEHUutCAO4+ea5B2ghpML1vSkxzf+Kc5Hu5sQ69SELB3FaEVOTACagme9\/9j57nMLTBR1mkOv1rCJQF1MAHWmeJDn6Ec682oN9RiynBmpK4pffA+atujFFpKxjWOCY6+KSKrZRbGPUtzjvaSWAhVwAALbUl8e9wfIQGmMjoGs04jIaKOgKc5Af8zZbgr0v5xhbyBpIaAJwVOqwyVwOaNKZWim48f9lahLHCxbpSaAo4YISTwI5OSGVCmao5VJdmLU42p2BEVXClKR+4NkHH+4SLPRbDhhPEgsyeO5Sh0rds7sGCPVB6GyaVMgYIzNAYnXzdABM4caK1E4gVkcDtYyOAnU3y8XFq6C8IdaJbqnGF8YSXDKsZzYRCblGFlFR4bRnQW6XxGLo9B0Av80PiJYAQtGENGk1XGbG2ooQg+aK4Q28ptlzGTi8idPDYaNaGazpkBCOUqB5CdCBWkoLxdnz4hJLIwXUtUlwam44p0UIY6anC9lusqZspKd\/MxpBKfIza7gqKnjCehF\/clMjAroOJSkor68IkA2IoufA23dVKWps3UyhwMtcFuKotlIboLHrHJzDa3gybuSftRG1MqNaPBYpwbsdXb8XOZaA2vHXvFVrP0sY80Ae85n0koBJHDB50hwSIGylY8g5aNlY+MpX+oOdwtSKaniCa++rbIgXKmpvdIooJn6Uq+PJOxqdGqvSokWUdh87S6LyluSIpajs11qrgSq2MRq1ov\/ZZXjcBcLTbBmMKZEQqKFvtrYb0bzdEHM3ZVgV5xYmSA92I3OZY\/bw+1OCVghLJfUsovJuiYxhxlq6OQw+M35mtNsPryh8WQb1jXe0KBgDW9rT3ipuCpQgeJbL+sooIHunC+dyx0w004oYOA6U8AxfZh0Q0rQkcKLtEA9IXtXGhlf2jVYE7aAa0+L1+zdV3zm5Z1oZ9nVg8x3u59EsQJX7FucBjjGAD4nhp+pX\/GC1YdM3e0F3Rbanf53ZyecrlTTdJ64gfVgBwkYNpUoHSyPF7F1u1aY8gMCEexzOFg2sc1OGRt81ZI\/LyBisNxl0zinz7laXhhwwlhlE9bIcDUl19eVS6bJtcUWzRBKHWcJ3d4kCqfKX66PWgnN54hZGdHeTNwZoVwhSJK1xyAGIKOLdhFJ09SoUOaKndmaZw9r2j67Okh+QsSf2ib61L018W\/xbLcCQXrQmeajl3kt5gP8urqppo2DmtxpY4VQ1zGZ65\/cuxAK+BYo0kbNWTCjbQ1eWyjZJovjJlTjjoz7sxCBQax3cu5yd\/vddFH3UdqN0rfUZ4kgufe6o6JvePv73zDpN8AHTvCCG\/zgCE+4whfO8IY7\/OEQj7jEJ07xilv84hjPuMY3zvGOEHv84yAPuchHTvKSm9wjAQEAOw==\" style=\"width: 717px; height: 34px;\" \/><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\"><img height=\"155\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAANMAAACbCAYAAAD4DK7YAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAABwUSURBVHhe7d1nlF1lFQbg+cN\/g\/jPJfIDFrJkSRHphAhSApJQpCgIUkVBI00EpCiCVOkQioJ0pCpYQu8dEkCCdBUFRBFQsAB+rufLPWEyyczcNveee85+17qLcOdmMnPvec\/e+93v3t9QCgSawH\/\/+9\/0zjvv5Mc\/\/vGP9Ne\/\/jW9+uqr6S9\/+csCD8\/9\/e9\/n\/\/af\/\/73+l\/\/\/tf47tUG0GmwKhAhNdffz098cQT6Re\/+EW68MIL00UXXZTOOuusdOihh6Z99903HXDAAQs89tlnn\/TDH\/4wv\/anP\/1puvzyy9Ntt92Wnn\/++Uyud999t\/Hdq4cgU83h4n7rrbfSyy+\/nO6\/\/\/509tlnpwMPPDB9+ctfTmussUZae+2101ZbbZW+\/vWvp\/333z8\/EOnkk0\/OpDrjjDPmP84888z83DHHHDOfXN\/61rfSLrvskjbddNO02mqrpQ022CB99atfTUcffXS65ppr0tNPP53+9re\/ZaINOoJMNcR\/\/vOfnKY98sgj6fzzz09f+9rX0nrrrZemTZuWvvnNb6Yf\/OAH6bTTTkuXXXZZjkh33XVXeuqpp9KLL76YH4j3r3\/9K7333nuZjMMf77\/\/fnrjjTfS73\/\/+\/x47rnn0uzZs9Mtt9ySrrzyynTBBRekE088MR188MFpp512Sp\/73OfS5ptvnr73ve+lG264Ib3wwguZ3IOYGgaZagIXuYsUgZAFcaZPn5722muvnJZJyW688cb0u9\/9Lqd2Xj9RkD7+6U9\/Sg8++GC69tprczQ75JBD0o477pg23HDDtPPOO6dLL700vfTSS\/m1g4IgU8XhYnzmmWfS6aefnrbbbru0xRZbpG9\/+9tp5syZORI8\/vjjpUixRLt77rknR8Pjjjsu7b777jk1FClFR6ngRBK8GwgyVRTUN+mZFE4E+sY3vpF+9KMfpeuuuy7f8csM6ePDDz+cU8IjjjgiRyqpoFpMRCsrgkwVg7rl9ttvzyT64he\/mA4\/\/PCswKl5BhFvv\/12uvPOO9Opp56a9t5777TtttvmtPSPf\/xj4xXlQZCpInA3V\/NQynbYYYf03e9+N11\/\/fVZbKgKiB\/SU6T60pe+lBXBP\/zhD42v9h9Bpgrgsccey3UQdYxKhkQiVFUhKpHhRV8p4HnnnZfFlX4jyDTAUJTr97ig9ttvv\/Sb3\/ymNm4DUPvpb+ljUSVvuummxlf6gyDTgILCteeee2YikbX\/+c9\/Nr5SP4jMhAqNZjUi9bIfCDINGHjfjj\/++JzSaXT268IpI9xg9thjj5z+\/fznP2882zsEmQYI5GJ2HiLDrbfe2ng2MBxMttwbRBgpYCu1lBQZCdmlvM9SZ7Xo3Xff3XjF2AgyDQD0jK644op815XOlLnXUhawL6mlCDKMus2A8rnuuuumD33oQ2nrrbfOiuEqq6ySNttss2yJGg9BppKDyHDCCSdkq43aaJDsNf0GE60II+371a9+1Xh2dOhpIZNatBByfI+VVlopzZgxI\/\/\/WAgylRivvPJKOuyww7K1hqM70DrMXvH+ESdYlcZSO5Fp\/fXXz273Av7+lClTsq1pPASZSgrzPxqvxiHKbv8pO3j6Zs2alW9KovtojWxRf+rUqWnVVVfNjgskFKXUXw899FDjVaMjyFRC\/Pa3v83FL5mXgzvQHYjuu+66a3ZRiEIjoTZVH02aNClNnjw5j6WsvPLK6Stf+UqaO3du41WjI8hUMjz66KN5oI5z2lxQoLsgJKihTjrppIV6cwhmvgrhqIJSPK0IfsAvfOEL497YgkwlAiLxnZ1yyim1bsJONJ588sn8PhtSHP4++7OaSWo9HMQHU8dS77EQZGoTvG8G6ciu3fDBcXXbn+COWYUR7rLDRK+xlJ\/85CfZJAze99VXXz0Tx6jKr3\/96+y4X3PNNXO2MJ5pOMjUJpgtvcmf+tSn8mh2J3DHI+FyNkRE6h2MdhiWPOecc+YPHlLtll566VwrffrTn06f\/OQn8\/6LZkY+gkxt4o477khLLbVUWnLJJbNLu90pUDm5xiIJPGqkzkH6VvvYcfHnP\/8594lkD8QHnxlV75JLLsmDh8cee2zacssts3qnKQ7qJMR59tlns1XLjbJZF0WQqQ3YD2dA7fvf\/34mgvy7HVfCm2++mf11+hq+Z2BsUNu8ZxrZxQWPKA888EAeeXdTQxSyNqeI91V\/CWFsWZJF+C93A2+j1xjnP\/LII3NTnOu+EwSZ2sC9996bx6gNpvkwpXs+zFagzlIf7bbbbqUacOsX1Csi82uvvZbfD6mv95YoY3LYWjCblKicSCD1Mkm88cYbpxVXXDF95jOfyTsjtt9++1wLaStImy+++OJc\/\/h8LJPxPX1vm5OQUhTzb9vvx37USXM8yNQG7JaTT\/uAPFhQKHCtCBE+YP0LCxqrDMW91ElEkdJqQEudCC5z5szJRf5VV12VI8RRRx2VlTTvCymaELDCCitkhU00IVn7OjIZDrTBiE3ovvvuy01V\/TnRyr8hzZOeNZt+W10m09Dfkx62gyBTi\/AhSR2YIaUNfFsf+chH8h2yWaeCu6Nu\/Lnnntt4ZjDBMeDOrv\/C+iTVddencrrJFPWJaCKdFU1EDuu8vG9qFQKA58jP1n1ZmmJylvXHsB+RoCAKEtpi5DNw8XcbvrfPRUSTUraKIFOLMPqwzDLL5BRNVJGCsJ14zuqs8eAO7e6n1nLHLiPczRGFsogoLl5EkRq5Efid1ScitF6N30cNojaxtVXKxZZjE6zUSTQhsJgK\/vGPf5yuvvrqXJ94L6Vxvqf9DgipWdrPkXupoPTxZz\/7WeOZ5hFkagEuML0gKt7wVMAFsMkmm2Qhwp\/HgnVb7n4uzH7Aher3QGQ1irrBRaxOUcgbXVA\/mAlSmIsm0i7WGuMIUi6kKWoTRb5o4oZCIVPb\/PKXv8wRxZJJEUXEluKJYoMwVi8qtlM\/BZlagDy\/2JU9vB\/kAlXwik5jCRHuxFQjd\/VuQzQpiOJnUy8UUYU87OdSn4gMCC1aMHGqRTQq11lnnSyqsM4QRdw0GG2NfyCWQt56YzWKfXyI4vu6KSBl0fisAryHbhLf+c53cibRLIJMLUDUcbdyFx95h3VRuVhHk7hd4DxhiudW83FEcbH6kClPRVQRUew\/cHG7mzJwWn2s8ejOutFGG6W11lorR81tttkmE1n01CBWbKsNTKMWp1UUNYrUSyEv+vr32u2hDTJsujUc6CbSLIJMPYJC3AYdxflwICWiIBiySIXcDdldjKkXlhZplBFq30MEoSAq5NUlPnRRRhF\/0EEHZVUMUSheinlqmZ16SCftIhKIWv69wOig0Hpf3ViaQZCpBxDJRAp9EhewdFHa5SJXZ1C7pF3SKwQRUdQlSOLvqVsQRRGvjlH0a0xK2Sy+V8wjHgMnoUAUrGM06TZkGd5\/DfpmEGTqAKLK8BSsULtc3NIuni\/FuWaiGRkFvMIdSahf7npF2kUWJh8jFtVLNEIUiiGFyTyNNDOiSW9BUPFZSX\/HQ5BpHCCKIl6PQ7\/DBS5lU5gr0C050SvxQBJ1CbWuIIlahXHS6xT+innNRiIEJ4X5GpFLDRTRpHyQfssKnJI4nsgyJD+XjztuhJLjw6fw6KP4gKsMxTXZ1l2f0saVIJoo4qVdooj3w9iyu5MOvGgi7WLJ11\/xOnWKqKIJi2gKedFEOuf1XuffCgwmSP0+\/\/HWqw254y6\/\/PLZ36TA9XBXZQh0Fx3UtEK+q4gXTaRd1CoFJaew3w9B9E\/kxGoVkcOFr8CnhiELeRhZ1CiIwlnMeUwWltKN11PiOhatpAqBwQUOiEyuh7GyhyHqkh4D1Wc4LOJzZ25WyegVDGiRhF2oOvFcBwa81BlkZz2gghwe\/t+jiCgeCOOhoHfDUMhLuxBFEV80GDuBlMCNSdQab9w5UH64PqTwY3kphzTeyKwuqOFwsfnL\/Eq9gpSTtV408UOznUhBRQYXZkEE\/9WzQZCCLAV5pGK+LgIxT6pPeMT0h0QqROxFF17\/Rx0VUakaEJ1cgzKW0WqnIekKMmnu6fp6uGB1xUm53YBowlovCiq6WVY0w3i71BrCp4dCj0UFGRClIIfl9Ijt4edDFD0Uq2x9r8KyUhavm6KV905UIl4EqgE3Rtcgl\/qiMERJQqblllsuixAKbg\/9j2bqJSKF3gZVSu9E2kXW1VmXKrqoEEDOiSgiikiCIIo6pkKCh9TM64sZFETx\/TQYpV3jKSllAucAFzlnQaA6UCOrp13Ti8L8NM+dfjRIj6RdVA1EkXaxo6g5FOgkYEW9aCKSGFFAEp16RBEaRSD\/hiIe4aRBnMJVU7mkkPJrAkcng2aBcsLNnqi0qDp4SCGPTDrqowEBDGkZ1hJBSOgs9kIeljoOUSTT0VfEk5rVWoyXIgoFpBd1Shkg1XRT0aztVMQIlA8sWfqI2igjMeTCt4GFTWU06OqLLgyTolLRf1IbFGQJzIObE2c58SRQPcikuMnV9yMDxJB6R62isz8WkIYypi9DYaOKBRaESHzhhRfmOxdRJFBNuP7pCiPH24cKdjUbXTQsCQjUN1b9wAcwaKdelDK3OmYRGBzggFS+WA9WoC1vnnqoWI9ElBhv02VdQMzRAHccZKC6oHLzZWohyUYKtG10tdCC9EvZoNLVPe0T4d1YhH93rkC1wbs6bdq0BSZxO3KNu4CoG0Ke7nCd6wQzRBQ8jdp2V0UFBgcauNo\/5sgKdGUEQ7\/IDgTG0ZtvvnmgGqzdgsjszeXqqOPvXzcYa9dbZcMr9IauzTNZ4OEbc1EwntbNRmPcQr0k1QtUH3qIAghXT+EU6hqZwB15+CnXei51ga09Rs2Hh\/1AtUG1NUVd9F27SqYCDK16V9I+joiqN3WJMbyIGtusV4F6wIzc9OnTs4oLE0Im0HNRP6gjNDKrPLXLp2WHgwldv3egHqAPaA\/JxmDCyAQ0eOkPhzhdvqp3bX03nkUtgmjW1gdWExgXKnbrTSiZCnCIIxObjXmmqsHof\/jx6gdWvGJPIfSETGAng7qC4xyTqzR64WgUw5RjjTQHqgeZl516hlihZ2QCKRBDLWFCfVGV5qZdFJZHhvOhfqDobbbZZvnPPSVTATseOCZI6KONAA8SePEMQYpQgXqBg9w8IPSFTCDftJTRRKrTFYYbBgcJfm4eRQJEIZEG6gOT5+pljdu+kQk0eR0qhVCmde16GDR4Ey2upOrYVxGoF\/SaDM2asO4rmQrY42w+ijWD3DhIIKQQViza4FEM1AtWNaiZ9BpLQSawL48yIkqRmAdlZwQLvtVjRpl7uWMwUA7wYjrM2sq80pAJpEzqD5tk7ZoYBDcBZwdlUh8tRvnrB6u3tXtsPi4VmQpYkG6K0Qqxso\/G26VWrD0b7dTAQHWBTAZCNe5LSSZgPWJxZ0WykLKskCvbCehnrRuZCEbEF8fr1NXgW5CptJGpADe22ShLShT545060Q9I8yiRRk7qlub5bBZbbLE0NDSUP586wjGpyETJLTWZCjjviK\/PBcvnVyYYEtMFp0ZaNV0nGN3++Mc\/npZYYom8Bm5R0KBXT9r865SSqrlEvAfGMGQlA0EmMGiITHxQnOhlQdFnskNd3lwnsIe5mBw5uqgRG58Tm9XkyZOzQ8SZX\/5cpWnk0vWZmoUoUMxIuYDLMCPFAWE1tMgZDogPYOIYecz7FCsMeDGdDu9s36pMYTNtu2H03QHRLhR9PiSFv6nefkNfDMGtkQ7MA4WTk37kDcZhBkg2c+bMSkxgu6lPmTIl\/3kgyQQ+JGZZErqJx35CTWcXQOx\/mAfpn32K0p+RnkuezF133TU7RizhGXQ4UM\/xQTCwZALqnmM0i9F4u+v6ARYoh8XZdxGYZ7GyXMZjpJOF4sk2xhg86MeTiqzcL9o3MNBkAmZZaZ+D0yyB7McZvMWxPLEWeR4QiCCz3nrrLXSD049SN+nLaX0MMih4lEq\/Cww8mQoUSwE97r777sazvYEjQKU1wxcS1h0yhZVWWmkhyZyA5AijMimy7UKNLF0tDlevDJnAneKUU07J3j6jHb06bIyHUB9FZKzyFqZW4D0RnVZdddWsdhrpR6Tll18+p3j9Ssm7Cb+TFE9mBJUiEziRQ7rFyXvcccflqDHRQNqTTz45ewm5hwPzoKbVqBWJVlxxxXz6pLSoKjccQ62Omn3yySfz\/1eOTAUYZA3sWQypCz+RUCMUi9zL5tDoN9RFlFcXnNpy0Ouk4TCyTskrphsqSyYgw4pOLPKGuDTWJgpqNv2TG2+8sfFMoMog\/zujTMpa3CAqTSaQm2uqOlDAjNREjcbr7vNoqQ8C1Ycoy4+pNdP1UzDKDgZLvj5vwESkYiZuzTRxZbz22muNZwNVBTXSNIPzyQrUhkxgRwPFjYxtRqqbq4zdnaSS3uDZs2c3ng1UFZwPn\/\/85xc4OqlWZAIWFk5fhKLAdXNGysmJzmiqQg8lMDrcOIvB1eE35NqRqYDw7NR4cvbcuXMbz3YG9dgWW2yRzj333IFZCBNoHdRJzVoHNQz\/nGtLJvCmcDfbLGvGplP3ArXQoGCc01RtcHdQiEc64mtNJpDmnX\/++fNH4w15dQLixtSpU+M4zorCDddBfpzvI88urj2ZCjiwyoCf\/XedbGbV3TdrpR7rpsARKAfcLNmkFtUCCTINAwGhOEfKjFI7cOeSBpDhY1iwepC9EK8YAkYiyDQCpE42EWkf+bOdc6REto022ihdccUVjWcCVQCnw3777Zdr4kUhyDQK1DysIhqxrZpXEdAEMHGjCu7owDxwiROrrr\/++sYzCyLINAaYMw844ICcI7c6Gm+mykae8OpVB3pL2imjiVRBpnFgRso5UtQbqp8Rj2ZAJvfGM0P2aq4qMHF44IEH8omXY6XuQaYmoDFnRkqI571zYkczsBPCts9Zs2Y1ngkMKghTRnrGap0EmVqAxSmWgeh+33PPPY1nR4coRtVDwCodiF03mIezY4QNbSwEmVqEtI9Zljjh+Jvx0j5Fq\/GPYrQ5MHiwSZigNF5DP8jUBuyCc5dyMJtVT2PNSHmtSOYD6dRdEeg9CEl2ilx77bWNZ0ZHkKkDGLXYc88907777jvmQnrpob6VJS+BwQHhyI3wkEMOacrNEmTqECZsC68Wsoz2ph9\/\/PFZYm9WvAj0H5dcckkes2h2h0iQqQsgg9sPZ6HKaKPxSOeDOemkkxrPBMoMdiGig9VxzSLI1EXYNU4+NyO1qNF4kYsJ9r777ms8EygrHFYuxWvlzK0gU5fhjsZ5Tu1jSRqe9hEjpIQzZsxYYNw5UC6YIKDAOhWwFQSZJgD8eNwS0j5m2eHEsYeCaGFEo9NhxED3waQsHXfkTavT0kGmCQKikFWlfWTx4edIFQcNRO+pXNBYd0yRz6ud3SBBpgkGx7m0j9rHLFtMZ9q35g4oUgXKAacA+kzaPWcryNQDuMs5YU7aZ9mK5q1aSv\/CfIyde4H+gpGVj9Ka63YRZOoRkIe1iPMYiRz65VABIx7qp3CW9w9ScB5KQ6HNNGdHQ5Cpx7BWVzSi9nFQmJk66KCDcsRqdrwj0D1IszXT3dA6PVQgyNQHUPfsXJOfSytIsSKUI0pC4esdZAYEh6OOOqory0iDTH2CKGTzq\/RCg9Cpgzx+\/T7sui7gUtHzMz0r5e4Ggkx9BqeED1XqR\/UznUtSj42wEwdEMgHtfW\/F4TAegkwlgDsjtU\/vyXpl0cp07sglh4HOUbQqEKnbpzwGmUoCap4mrmLY8n+qnxqKBSnQHRB\/TEo7GnQi3PtBppKBukc6X3nllfN5qSJWlY6u7Bcop07iP+GEEybs\/KwgUwlhNJ5DYvLkyfm0cvv3unn0TZ2g9ixORXeowkTuMQwylRSahzfccEM+beGjH\/1oTvusbw40D04TLQjOE7vBJzrCB5lKjqeeeirP1UyaNCmfVIdg0YsaH88991w2rKpBrWnrBYJMAwApngneZZZZJq2xxhr5BPniuPzAwtAEZyxWe6pBe4UgUwkgfdOwNZDmIqA4SeusVybhSvlEI2fmbrLJJuljH\/tYXtBieC3k8w\/ggDn9I9uE1Jyvv\/564yu9QZCpBHACnYsAodZee+00NDSU+01IZRHL8KLZpiM73BZffPG04YYbpqOPPjrNmTOn8dV6whySHYZEBu+Nw7\/7gSBTyWCX9Sc+8YkxxQYdfBIv4q222mrZNcEoy2tWN7Bf2blRqHWU0H4hyFQyuMMi01h7+IC3zyoqRFp33XXzAVwuKurVog7iqhrI3fZ\/S3cPPPDA3EfqN4JMJYPdEcsuu2zTG4wcDsAeYzzeiYfSHOqfE+6quKPv1ltvzeZUNSWlTkrXyQxSNxFkKhlaJRNYAuJwAHdo7nNqn4iFWEilzhpkUDPJ235H\/kW\/m3XF9hWWCUGmkqEdMgGRQopn8xFPnz6LzUgUQhcfF4Wzdkcet19W8Creeeed+Xcwc0ShYwBGqrKRqECQqWRol0zAOsNt7hwhKh9BAslsm5UG8vpJAR3edt111+Vx7TJJ66Rsvze3glTOz7zlllvmiGsspewexSBTySC6fPjDH8535XYxd+7ctM8++2Rpvdi0gzTPPvtsXverf7XVVlvlg46R7rzzzsuny\/t6L8klffPziaSUOD014\/x6aX52UUhzelB6aUGmkkFkIfMiRCd466238l6D4pCuYmGL5q9tSOoo9ZR\/a\/31188eQH0uTgvR0Spnxb7hRXsSRLh2xkGojiIOW5QNQBrNF110UTr77LNz6il123TTTdO0adNyBNKYNmdU1lRuLASZSgZ3YRdgN\/x3vpcdE\/abi0Ajd\/QhB5LozYiEogNyrbnmmmnKlCl59ZUaTM3iHCrk1M+67LLLMkHHeiCMekdKqSEtvfS9kWattdZKU6dOzd\/Xa9Vxb7zxxsCPmgSZaoAnnngiRx3q3v333994dmEgsYtaU5g156677sqkEK2kXWqY6dOnZ3+g0RAN40U9fO2zn\/1sPgyOXC\/imMuiwEnrXn755bxUBpGrNJ4fZKoJXLyii+auVKrZPX2im4iBZNI1RCNsjPdwhI5\/09+RcuoFVX2vRZCpRlCHIBLXgGjTzWUigSBTLUF8IJ\/rPz366KONZwOdIshUU0jDnBpPxTNwGHsmOkeQqcZAIGoa1Y5S161ljHVFkCmQ7r333pz2Uftiz0T7CDIFMjRK9aKkfRrHsa+vdQSZAvOh72Oeit3I8SqxXqw1BJkCC4GNyKwQf9\/w40MDYyPIFFgkeOmsEdaTsu0n1ouNjyBTYFRwPRg25JpgB7LUMTA6gkyBceEcKQ1eHrtBGS7sB4JMgabw+OOPp8MOOyzv9bN3IrAwgkyBpkHdmzlzZk77DBTaVxf4AEGmQMswSmG0gkAxckaqzggyBdqCPXXFsaF22AWCTIEOYELXJK1JXktbyrK\/rl8IMgU6goG\/q6++OgsT7Eh1npEKMgW6Aiu6ZsyYkXc9tLOmrAoIMgW6BiMcRuOtLnYAwaCs6OoWgkyBrgKBLr744ryB1XE4dThEoECQKTAhMCPFLOtkjrE2IlUJQabAhMFKLzvzqH16U1aJVRlBpsCEAoGkfU48998qy+dBpkBPYM0yUaK6SOn\/0L0zeZIS7VMAAAAASUVORK5CYII=\" style=\"vertical-align:middle;\" width=\"211\" \/> <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>8 cm\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>10 cm\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>12 cm\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>16 cm\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"d","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu9":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>7<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>1<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>If <i>x<\/i> and <i>y<\/i> are non-negative integers and 5<i>x<\/i> + 4<i>y<\/i> when divided by 9 leaves a remainder of 2, find the remainder when <i>x<\/i> - <i>y<\/i> is divided by 9. \n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>4\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>6\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>8\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Cannot be determined\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"a","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu10":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>7<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>1<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><b><\/b>How many ordered pairs of integers (<i>x<\/i>, <i>y<\/i>) satisfy the equation   <img Width='52' Height= '31' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAADQAAAAfCAYAAACoE+4eAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAQySURBVFhH7ZhfSFtXHMeDmiomka6Dro51rx2sQgfxpUMN1HXo3tq1ugfRPdlZ695qjGH1xapVC7O1e9EotiYTEdRBZ1yde6jtnJ0iIiaaqB2oNU5UMvyv353f8SQkeKU2N5c62Ad+cH+\/c\/K9+Z57cu45UeEA7lRUoKvLLrLwoIQmUVxcjJGREX4taai5+RHUajUslgZRkY8SmkRJyS1ERETgj4EBngcZmp+fx+VLl6BSqRAVFYX792tFS+gooUk4HGP49Px5rhsZGYlfnvTwepAhu70Ler0e\/f39ePfECVRWVYuW0FFCk7hXU4O0tHQ86+vjA+WbykGGNjc3xRWg1WjCcnMlNAmfrofNAHpKkoZ8UGedVhu2mxNKaBLTU1P\/GwoLb91Q9LFjKK+4IyryUUKTmJqc5IYeP\/6Z5wcaej8+Ht\/X3BMV+SihSfz18iXi4uLwRGrZ9rG7u4u\/FxawuroqKvJRQpPY3t6Gx+PBxsYGzyUNHZY+9g54+rRPZEcDWYaKjEbcvGkU2dFAlqHqqipUVlaJTB4tLS3Iy8uTDIfDIXq9HpXL5YLNZoPVaj0wWltbsb6+zj\/w54sXKC0t5ZGamooLF1L9ud3ezfsMDg5K6gRGoCaxuLiI6elpyVhbW+N96LcipeUL8qHq7e1FTk4OsrKyDozc3FysrKxwURoA+jIUmRkZuHo1w58PDQ3xPiQupRMYgZrE8PAw2tvbJYOMEPSksrOzJfUoqE3WlKPzTXl5hcjk0d3dzbTKJYOe0mGRZcjMDlYmU7HIjgayDLkmJjDB4ighy9DbIv\/6dSQmJvrDYDCws1Ea6ust\/01DdXV1KCws5GE2m\/EZW21pP9fZ+VOwoUm3G42NjfB6\/+H51tYmGhoseP78d56\/KTs7O2zFa4bT6RSVvVpTUxPGxg7\/bnkdH505g8zMr\/h1kCHa6JFTo7GI51+z5ZzyQbEcvynbW1tQs+PxtWvfiApw924113S7J0VFHjfy8xGlVmNpaZnn+6YcbWe0Wh3Kysr4jXt6fhUtoWFISUFKioFf03snJjoat2+X8VwutJzTdww8Y+0zRLvh+FOneMfa2geiGjoFBTfwwenT\/PrbggKcPPkeP0qEA1NREf9rbGlpSVQkDM2\/eoV3jh9HJJsqvi2HHH54UAudLg6jo6N8kKxWm2iRBx1HPmQDdYXtVAIJMkRP5+zZj3Hu3CfsS+jw3a0S0RI6v7GtVWxsLBISEqDXJ4qqfMbHnXyAbLYfRWUPvyGv18vmezK0zAitcmaTiX9gZmZG9AiNudlZxMREcy3fv5vh4NHDh1zT6RwXlT38hjo7OpCcnIwBtpsmFhY8+PziRbY57OC5HDTsCV3+8orIwkNbWxvS07\/A8vLe6uZj328o3Fjq6\/hIulxuUVEWxQzNzc0iKSkJGo2GvdnrRVVpgH8BevktrtdWSLkAAAAASUVORK5CYII=\"\/>  ?\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>2\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>4\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>6\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>5\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"d","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu11":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\"><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>7<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>1<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">If log<sub>3<\/sub> |<i>a<\/i><sup>3<\/sup> + <i>b<\/i><sup>3<\/sup>|&nbsp;<\/font><\/font><\/span>&minus;<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">&nbsp;log<sub>3<\/sub> |<i>a<\/i><sup>2<\/sup>&nbsp;<\/font><\/font><\/span>&minus;<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">&nbsp;<i>a<\/i><i>b<\/i> + <i>b<\/i><sup>2<\/sup>|&nbsp;<\/font><\/font><\/span>&minus;&nbsp;<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">log<sub>3<\/sub> |<i>a<\/i><sup>3<\/sup>&nbsp;<\/font><\/font><\/span>&minus;<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">&nbsp;<i>b<\/i><sup>3<\/sup>| + log<sub>3<\/sub> |<i>a<\/i><sup>2<\/sup> + <i>a<\/i><i>b<\/i> + <i>b<\/i><sup>2<\/sup>| = 2, then find the value of <img height=\"38\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAE8AAAAmCAYAAACFz8YUAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAh4SURBVGhD3Zp5UNRHFsfFa0sih9kqQHQ9YKEiWbMbRIENLgrKZSQgGI0H+UNUwKCUIhXQKo8AWSVYpZSsHLIaURcQjAEUsEoFRQTXC1RE0AVLMKCCB6Ic8t1+PQ0Dw+FwDpNPVRe\/12+G38z3193vve4ZhkGiqKgI2dnZwlJ+7t+\/j0ETLz4+Hps3bxaW8hMbGzt44kVHR2PdunXCko+nT58iJCQEoaGheP78uegdHBIS4hEUFISsrIuipz3h4eFDV7wXL17AwMCAfYFg+LERazxjBmpr3wjvwOL\/\/ff43HgGDh06hAm6E5CckiI8Uoa0eNVspNGHJ96\/b4KqqipKS8u4PdDQEvPgwQN+\/eWCBdiwwYdft2VIi9cWV1cXLF+2HM3NzaKn7xxmD+ZMWpqwOic97Qx0dXVRUiIRsi1KId6yb76Bk5OzsPqHd2\/fYtiwYQhkS0JXnPrlF0ydqoecK1dET3uGhHi1ta+Rl5eHu3fvih4J7969g6uLC+wdHPDq1SvU1NSw6fteePvG7YICqKio8GBw9epVtr6+FB4JiSdOQEtLC5dYalVXV4c3rMmicPEiIyKgN3UqrK2tMX36X+Do6MiiajX35d+6hT9NnAg7Ozvmt4KtrR2Pvh8iwN8ft9h7u+P4sWNcvLlz58LS0hI6Ojo4d+688AKOCxfCmAUMe3t7zJkzB8eP\/0d4pChUvIrycmizpxsT829u19RU86l0IjGJ2zTKaI2jEUhPn5o8a94CNlJpxHSHl6cHRo4chWvXr3Pb2soKRkaf8muiqamJt5b7NjY2Co8UhY+8\/Px8Htkoqgb+8AMXL\/X0aeGVH0prHj16xBuNlhOJia12Z1\/8U6NpcHP7VljA7l27oKGhKSz5UKh4MQcPYtKkyViyZAl27NiBpeyvispwPHnyRLxCfpKTk7F69Wrepk6ZgoVs+tP1mrVrUVlZJV4l4fXr11AdMwYpqdKH5L5qFf8sPUGh4qmrqcHbe4OwgG\/d3PgX6Gs2stjVFbksAHVFLoueNMLPnb\/AbVoK1MaOhe9mP27LCxfv8OHD2MWG7UAjK565mRk+++yvSE9Ph5+fH\/9CNiwo9JX58+YxYaSLvyz\/\/PFHfi8LCwuksMrBigUNemgUzXsCF4++kKmpmegaOGTFe\/z4MVt3VsKBLfB79+7lEfDAgQPC23uOHT3KKpFSYXUkISGBB6kIdi+K5F7sM1VVfTiKy9Iq3vz5NqILbM2pAI3GI0eO4NmzZ6JXQklJCQ6ytSozKwsVFRUoKrovPB+ms4ChzHQQLyszE+rq6iznms7yHGN2rYHTZ85wXywTc\/To0WyUmkJfX5+\/ztTUnPvk4Xcrnp29A5rfN2O8jna7UsjZyQkff\/xHnpxShPrOez3vr65+Dh1tbfztc2NuywOJ5+XlJSzlZ\/\/+\/RLxvmKCVVZW8oX04iVpgvlfVrpQH+Vhw4cPZyVUofAAnh5rYWj4ibCkdFVCkXg+Pj58up89e1apG+2KR7DqqFU8WutIqNxcaZgvKMjnokUciJCIV9i9eNHRUXwJcHZ2Rk5O+4KaxKOd5JycHGzdulWpW1xcHCIjIyXi2Tss4Jm4quoYeK+X5l4+G9Zj1KjRKCsr49N2vdjXelNbi4ms7qQNwxZo\/83Q0BCF9+4hOioS01ka0hYSz9PTU1jKT+u0NTP\/O+848vPPfPQ5On4FFxcXfh0e\/i\/uO5mUiFEjR8Lc3BxG04xYbUjXkvcRNF2pDiwpKYYrS1R9fdufV\/Q2YFRVVeHhw4fCGjyopqZDnq7gAeM6K46zWOrRQs7ly9i4cSOfYteuSQrn+vp6\/o+Ki4t5CkNTe46lJWbP\/gf3tyUlJZlNWyd4sFFGH6CF3ogXtm8f33FZtGgRVq1yR31Dg\/AMLJkXLvBB4saqHisra75Oy8LFE9fdQiOKUpM1a9byvbXMzAt8VO7eHSJeQYc1VdgTukdYwNiPxrbLA3sqXgMTytbWFvkFBdzW1NREesZZfj3QeLEHv1\/MuNmzLbBpky+\/bovc4hHpaWkwNDCAnp4eK2cmsZHph8amJuEFaqqrMX68DoJZ+bN92zZeetWytbGF3k5b4s7t29BmqVExS9L7izt37rDZVCyszmlkD5By2ri4eNEjpUfitUBVR13dW2G1h4b3zp07ERgYyEZi++qkt+LdunkTE3R1ERt7VPT0nSYWHDXYTPIP2CJ6OkJB0YwVBN95e4ue9vRKvN7SnXgU6WnzURbaETYxMUF29mXR0z\/8jwUgWnby8q7y5UEW2h+0tbHBvn1hoqcjChevvLwcK1Ys54vzrFmz+BEf7bcRL1++hIaaGqaxyE7By8PDg9fW\/UHyr79ixIgRWLx4Mb83bRCUlT0SXsDezpaVon\/g96X0Kj09Q3ikKFS8ehaJ6VB75sxZeMxELGGRnEZDSMhP3E\/r5cmTJ\/lOc0xMDG+\/\/VbJfX1lS4A\/v1dUVDQ\/n50yeXK7zZGMjAwkJSW13jc\/XxK02qLwkUc\/\/LnJpiblcTdu3MC4ceOwbft24R04aC2ztp4nLCA4KAgamuOEJR8KFa+stBRLly7FF19Y8OlDiTWNhtTTkl2cnkDT0N3dvUPz9fXlOWpbGhrqoaGhjtijx0QP4LtpE7S0tIUlHwoVz3Hhlyzt0W9NZ6iCIfF6c4ZBuSdtrso2+l+yJ26U9tB9cq7kih7gz\/p6+PrrJcKSD4WKZ2drg09YMKDAcOnSRXykqorxuhNYmdd\/P6nojCgq6Jl4K1au5KXfloAAbhcW3hOvkA+FildUdA9mZma80fSlKbZs2fJOjwr7kz2hofxkjU7MKMKbmMzEeVaO9RSFBwyipwcv\/Ulf7j0kxFNWBlU82jykRPf3QlhY2OCJl5qaiuDgrn\/SpWycOnUK\/wd8JdJ+0Pf9cwAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==\" style=\"vertical-align:middle;\" width=\"80\" \/> . <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>log<sub>3<\/sub>41 - 2\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>log<sub>3<\/sub>41 - 3\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>log<sub>3<\/sub>43 - 1\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>log<sub>3<\/sub>43 - 2\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"a","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu12":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><b><\/b><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>2<\/i><i>:<\/i> Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>How many times does the digit 6 appear in the first 1000 natural numbers?\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"300","CORRECT_ANSWER":"300","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu13":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>3<\/i><i> <\/i><i>a<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>d<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>4<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><b><\/b>Rajesh and Ramesh are running on two different circular tracks. Both of them took the same time to complete one round each on their respective tracks. Then they interchanged their tracks and Rajesh completed two rounds in the time in which Ramesh completed one round. Find the ratio of the speeds of Rajesh and Ramesh. \n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <img Width='16' Height= '15' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAABAAAAAPCAYAAADtc08vAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAG4SURBVDhPjZK\/b0FxFMUf7VQGERJqUha66Ez\/hNIFIaERNgTtZNFFYmnFbraIRFhI\/JhMYtAuhBAhpEK0QysGcdr3fd9omnjST3KTe859OXn33cfgCKVSCYFAAKFQ6GBFIhEcDfB4PGi1WhgOh7zFGzAajeB0Oqnihzcgm80iGo1SxQ9vQCwWQyaToYpjPB5juVxSxcEb4HK50O\/3SV+rVnGp10OpVEIqlcLtvsPn1xeZHQxYrVaw2+2kXywWYBgGZssteYNqpUJ05P6BzA8G1Ot1+P1+0s9mUzgcDownE6JZrk1GGAxXpD8YkEgkkE6nqfrL\/O0NpycneHpOEk0Cut0uarUaMVh8Ph+azSZVv3y8v0Or0cBoNGG34zymWCxCp9NBIBCQ3bfbLaxWK9brNfcEpdfr4UKtxo3Zgs1mQ92fgE6ng8FgAKFQiHg8jul0Cq\/XS8ccry8vOP+5QOzxkTq\/7L9BMBiEQqFAKpVCMsntxzKfzyESnUGvv0S5XEY+n0cul0Oj0SDzfQD767JriMVitNtt6gLFQgEqlQparRZyuRwymYyUzcad+c8VwuEwJBIJVf8B+AYWFidGOzWoXAAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==\"\/>   : 1\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>2 : 1\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>1 :  <img Width='16' Height= '15' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAABAAAAAPCAYAAADtc08vAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAG4SURBVDhPjZK\/b0FxFMUf7VQGERJqUha66Ez\/hNIFIaERNgTtZNFFYmnFbraIRFhI\/JhMYtAuhBAhpEK0QysGcdr3fd9omnjST3KTe859OXn33cfgCKVSCYFAAKFQ6GBFIhEcDfB4PGi1WhgOh7zFGzAajeB0Oqnihzcgm80iGo1SxQ9vQCwWQyaToYpjPB5juVxSxcEb4HK50O\/3SV+rVnGp10OpVEIqlcLtvsPn1xeZHQxYrVaw2+2kXywWYBgGZssteYNqpUJ05P6BzA8G1Ot1+P1+0s9mUzgcDownE6JZrk1GGAxXpD8YkEgkkE6nqfrL\/O0NpycneHpOEk0Cut0uarUaMVh8Ph+azSZVv3y8v0Or0cBoNGG34zymWCxCp9NBIBCQ3bfbLaxWK9brNfcEpdfr4UKtxo3Zgs1mQ92fgE6ng8FgAKFQiHg8jul0Cq\/XS8ccry8vOP+5QOzxkTq\/7L9BMBiEQqFAKpVCMsntxzKfzyESnUGvv0S5XEY+n0cul0Oj0SDzfQD767JriMVitNtt6gLFQgEqlQparRZyuRwymYyUzcad+c8VwuEwJBIJVf8B+AYWFidGOzWoXAAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==\"\/>  \n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>1 : 2\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"a","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu14":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>3<\/i><i> <\/i><i>a<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>d<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>4<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>If <i>p<\/i>, <i>q<\/i> and <i>r<\/i> are integers such that <i>p<\/i><sup>2<\/sup> + <i>q<\/i><sup>2<\/sup> = 221 and <i>q<\/i><sup>2<\/sup> + <i>r<\/i><sup>2<\/sup> = 125, then how many ordered triplets (<i>p<\/i>, <i>q<\/i>, <i>r<\/i>) are possible?\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>0\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>3\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>12\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>24\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"d","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu15":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\"><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>5<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>7<\/i><i>:<\/i> Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<img alt=\"\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,R0lGODlhIgEuAPcAAP\/\/\/0dHRwAAAN3d3SMjI8PDw2lpaaenp4mJiZiYmNDQ0LW1tXp6ehEREezs7FdXVzQ0NAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAACwAAAAAIgEuAAAI\/wABCBxIsKDBgwgTKlzIsKHDhxAjSpxIsaLFixgzatzIsaPHjyBDihxJsqTJkyhTqlzJsqXLlzBjypxJs6bNmzgXBhAgYEDOhAR+Ch2asoABAEaJEuSptKlTkEmbHgAQ9KnVqxYJ+HxaFavXrwt7Xu0KtqxZAV7Jml17FQFPAQGsqmVLt67du3jz6t3Lt69fvQkUZFywwOBbphUDDy7M8DBaioojEv4r0wACggGmAnDs8+1lAAd4xgVg4KhHywsN8PyssHTBtx1RFzwwGjRP0wNdU3bJADdVAZoHIjiaGamAApuRE9AcIEHH3gtD+ySAXKdzkdALuh09QCz1gs13s\/8s0MDBwAAFlhPsbvD7caqau28VqHquQ\/LmFSIYLVuhfIWhCcAaRPjNZtloB\/hW0H\/ipRTAgAKpl1twAqV3nli54TZAXAhQ+NCDDIUWoYII6YZQVfYxBOJB+wk03G0HmdhgSQUIkB9BEgLA3npidaccawpgKJyHDdV4Y2u3kXhQkPMBJZGRCLUIgFsCAWcQkzOaZEBtOAaXIEE1DnRAVVJGeJ1AO020ZUQrMkTAmVFC2NCaUY42HJpyUgVnliE1kGeOBgRXAJc1+hSAb3QOtKFEfhYZF4MMJRpjngw1WmeFj71nkKR8fuTjQTmiNxABhyEXIJcAJPDYoEihytCnc\/L\/RGRCqiYU6ESwslhbgEqm+phDJgqA23EEUDpQmF22dhQCKeIqZEVu2bfAsx3VKBhpPDVJ2nxlCjStthxZe1B3b4Gr0LcaiavjW9UZNGaFaRpHlbGYRuQasxtBWlFxLP76UZDtRmllty766xHAzs5KpUYIw2dbQmIhsJ+pcRGgmrCYrkYuWepdzKVbAjK7068jU\/iucZ2Jtu4A+JJm2sVywgzAyHkuHJIAex4UoH02g4RzRz1j9LOFEQaM2VToSUzaVAQEVWhyDyM76gFE80vfsu8VS1pcTw8UcVwg+ihfy\/cGlevDn7apncEeCdiQiP2O5PZDNTo2d8Ec3e21uVNe\/4YWq1rNW2XAYUodIdVsXz1lVa59N\/OAIFo9+NiME6eZjCu6pjZBQdvt+eeHvUavQDvHvRToqDsmOtD+pv756opaidCgrG5GVYSfvQcyU4Y7fGpBZSvu2IC02W4cu5QrTupbvmnt8uMCyz16aMgRPGXieY+OUHcKY0+R3poCpfTjpjl\/3H+FG5zjzBQG\/7zjBnE\/moTn93Sy5rNC\/\/zmwnmv0c8K+Riqgta2nF2EgBYBoI6alZvATYlf5ivA09LUu+UUj30EcZ9r6CS7UcluYPUbANww1jLnkQ4t3NOfQRC4kRoZTSIsTFf4NBLDJ83wbV2RWgRnxhMXbsZf6hmZgv9CY5nKoWk1K\/wVyPaDgP8I8WUwAh4SVVgQdX2kaxWxokewKMNrYQSLROuURrrDmCoexmxvYY6sotQAjJDRIGEEWXV29xoPIaCNHXnjsXhSFXJ1cHHawaMYQWJChBTnO9JZGLUE8oAHZKSQtuljTwpXlQDURjUeauRHChk4ECESQ91RiyYHCRIGQABAruqJbiQ3kAbkLyKmBFNmqnLBGV4wQesDgCs\/EktFoclDGCqWWnZJSk8tclTaKl7L9Oat8mREX6Ah0\/wCxi+0rG8BzvSIvmqklgtK7GTNPFIxOcI\/0qFKakKU0wMYsJHNnUxK8NPNrda3zpDwr2XyWmA0CVJ7z3H+qwHmupWY7JPLAjEMoAQ5WS2r0ybHVMeg\/9QWssC5O7hUKJv+9EgCXEWV+XxJTEfpnQMgUEaNbDShkhThY0TVHs2MtKQfOelmfLKmj86mKi\/NaEh6I87WHcZQPSTISF9pEZ6SritytM1buKSeoZaEp3XL1E8HCgCnJuo0JAXgW0QU4MUtahUiXD1JViUS1qua9axoTata18rWtrq1QQEBADs=\" style=\"width: 290px; height: 46px;\" \/><\/p>","OPT1":"384","CORRECT_ANSWER":"384","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu16":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>5<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>7<\/i><i>:<\/i> Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Gabbar sold his gun at a loss of 10% and his horse at a profit of 20% and incurred an overall loss of Rs.2000. Had he sold the gun at a loss of 5%, instead of 10%, he would have made an overall profit of Rs.2500. Find the price (in Rs.) at which Gabbar sold his horse. Rs.<\/font><font style='font-family:Rupee Foradian;'>\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"42000","CORRECT_ANSWER":"42000","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu17":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>5<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>7<\/i><i>:<\/i> Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><b><\/b>What is the product of the HCF and the LCM of 96, 216, 432?\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"20736","CORRECT_ANSWER":"20736","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu18":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><b><\/b><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>8<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Rajan\u2019s monthly telephone bill consists of a fixed amount towards monthly rent and a variable amount that varies directly with the number of units of calls made during the month. If Rajan made 100 units of calls in a certain month and 150 units of calls in another month, and received bills of Rs.500 and Rs.650 for the two months respectively, find the number of units of calls made by Raju in another month, for which he received a bill of Rs.950.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>200\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>250\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>300\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>350\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"b","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu19":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\"><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>9<\/i><i>:<\/i> Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">If <i>a<\/i>&nbsp;<\/font><\/font><\/span>&lowast;<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">&nbsp;<i>b<\/i> = <img height=\"33\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAB8AAAAhCAYAAAAh3nDkAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAQxSURBVFhH7ZdbTBRXHMaX0thECSrEIvbJVGxoLSEt9MFdCpSAkTeblrJgy2pBRS4BwZLYYEkoCAsIC0tIQB7sAwmgXHZJCILa0stDWfCCQdxNIIFNbLgWIV3uX8\/5c5zNLIuRNGDS+EtOMt9\/zsy3c86ZM98qsIWsrq7CaDQiLS0NhYVaUbWzpeacpcVFeOzdi\/QLGaJi5z+ZLy8vY35+XijnWCxmKBQK3LlzV1TsbGi+yH7xysqKUGtD6Eh7eztOnPhcKOeUlBRj565dQslxaq4rK0NFRQWqqqqQl5eHpKQkekpHbjQ2IjDwE6GcExIcjKCgT5GdnQ0\/Pz+cPXsOz2Zn6ZzMfGlpCcciIpCZmUlmjwcGaMiior4SPeR03rqFkJBQodbz9\/Q03N3d4e\/vj9raWuSzB+H30xYV0XmZuSbuG3z0cYBQgPnJIHVuamoWFaDp5k1UV1dTO5+YiEOHfCTN29DQkOgJGAytdH1f3z1RAfbsdkd0tJqOJfNH\/Q+pY0+PSVTYfBUXw8XFBRMTk6ICFBYUIDk5mVpkZCS8vQ9Imrd79++LnsApTRwOH35PKGBubo7dT4HSMh1pyfx84jl4ee0XCphl87LfywvBLxjW211dCA39TCg5K2za3t63Dxe\/yxIVwMhGwtX1TTx9+hdpyfxYRDgNIWd8fAxnEhJoJDIyL2JkZITqjvApOHpUKZScP37\/ja7v739Emq+hD48cga68nDRHMr9aUkKd1Wo1UlJSUFNTQ\/r48UiMjo6KXnJeZG7q+RM+Pj5obm5Gb28vUlNTcbW0VJxdQ7bgOjs7UVdXJ70KbW1tsFqtdOyMmZkZ2QJzhJ83GAy0HzjrJzPfbl6bvxIUfCE0sj26vr5+W1trK9v9TCYTitheq9Vqt7WVsY\/X6wX3Svj\/mvMY1tLSwnJCHOLj49dFsS0152bjY2P0gTrD4pMjWz7sz6NYd\/evomJnQ3OeOhYWFoRynl5fhsKCK5TjnLHOnIdIHvQq9HpUVlYiKysLp09\/6zS9vgxBKiVUqiAWSjPo+x4TE4tpFiw5MnOb7R+olEpcvvwDaYvFQkMWe\/Jr0ptlcnISbm5uCAgIpC1Vz+I4v9+P7OE4MvOoL7+AUqkSyj5fBoNRVICfrl+n7XijZjabRc+1pMOvHxh4LCosve7ZjWh1DB1L5n19vdTxwYOHogJcyc\/HG66umBLDxCnX6WgqNmrPMxvnZGwMfN\/\/QCgeSp+Rh15fSVoyT0iIh\/eBd4QCpqam4OnpgfDwCFHZHMts7Xh6eODSpe9Fhf\/DacCOHW+xgDpBWjLn6fXgwXfpmAdGjUZDmT09\/QKGh4epvhm6f\/mZnnJw8Alpm80GX19fXLtWS5ojmTc01NMrwXei3NxcdHR00C8\/xVY6\/9O4WazWUYSFhaGr6zatg5ycHDSxJGsH+BcZAytu9RxiiQAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==\" style=\"vertical-align:middle;\" width=\"32\" \/> , find the value of (18&nbsp;<\/font><\/font><\/span>&lowast;<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">&nbsp;12)&nbsp;<\/font><\/font><\/span>&lowast;<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">&nbsp;(6&nbsp;<\/font><\/font><\/span>&lowast;<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">&nbsp;3). <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"4","CORRECT_ANSWER":"4","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu20":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>0<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>If the surface area of a sphere increases by 96%, find the percentage increase in the volume of the sphere. \n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>274.4%\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>174.4%\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>42%\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>142%\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"b","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu21":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>1<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>3<\/i><i>:<\/i> Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><b><\/b>Eight years ago, Surya\u2019s age was three times his son\u2019s age. If the sum of their present ages is 64, after how many years from now will the age of Surya be twice the age of his son?\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"4","CORRECT_ANSWER":"4","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu22":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>1<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>3<\/i><i>:<\/i> Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><b><\/b>A train travels 2<i>x<\/i> km at 40 km\/hr and another 3<i>x<\/i> km at 60 km\/hr. Find its average speed (in km\/hr) for the entire distance. \n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"50","CORRECT_ANSWER":"50","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu23":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>1<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>3<\/i><i>:<\/i> Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><b><\/b>Let \u03b1 and \u03b2 be the roots of the equation <i>x<\/i><sup>2<\/sup> - <i>a<\/i><i>x<\/i> - <i>b<\/i> = 0, where \u03b1 < \u03b2. If \u03b1 + \u03b2 = 3 and   <img Width='79' Height= '31' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:Image\/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAE8AAAAfCAYAAACmupBxAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAX7SURBVGhD7ZlbTJRHFMcRa+OlER\/ESqtNtEkFtMUHb9AHYy3QUEFqenmpPggCCqVAqMQo3pIii2IrrYs02rIUCypo09YFmoIBrFYQ5LYaKkVYArLITVDwAvw7c5hd0f2wC\/uxq9ZfMmHPmfm+2f0zM+fMjA0e4fbt2ygoyIdCocC9e\/eFVx76+vqg0WgQGxuLmpoa4bUunZ2dUKvVSEhIEB7TMRJPq9XCd7UPZs50EB756O3tRUzMl7C1tcXVJ0S8K1euYMmSxVi8ZKnwmI6ReJz98fswdaodGyn9wiMff1dXw8bGBheKioTH+gQFBmCeo5OwTEdSvL1xCtjZTRsT8aoqKp848QIDNsDRyVlYpiMpXpwidszEq6yoeOLEC9jg\/1y80fJcPDOQVbx9e+NIvP7+AeGRD01VFYlXVFwsPNaHBwxH5\/nCMh1J8TZ\/EUk\/sLf3jvDIx59nz9K7886cER7rMjAwQKnZ9On2bKb1Ca9pGInX1NTIom0cQkJCUFhYyBLle6LGfLq6upCeno7g4GCksb83b94UNdajtrYW26OjER4RgdLSUhLTVCRH3kjhHd6\/L+9u5GlAFvHKLl3C+vV+wvr\/IIt4f50\/Dw8PT2GZT3t7O1paWiTLnTvyr8OjRRbxilna4e3tIyzz2b17NxvJ6yXLxYslopX1sTnLol94eDjCwsL+s\/B2FSxP41RWVhp+kLe3N2bPfs1gb926jdpwenp6sGPHDsn3DS1KpVI8YTrKgwcNfT5aTp9Wi1agwLRlyxbJfk0t8fHxRtHY5vr16yhmOZephU8dzt27dw1TKTsri6at3m5ra6M2HB6teRSTetfQUsXyPz0qlYqOxKRKdXW1aDUoir7PRws\/WtPDp3pJSYlkv6aW8vJyo0gs27T18npfWOaTk5ODtLQ0yaLVNohW1qO+rg7nzp2XR7yiCxfg6\/uBsJ59fFatokRfFvH4tNDpdMJ6PP39\/SwRbxLW00lDQwOiNm+WRzxTOcZ2FV5eXti5cyc8PT2Rm5snaiwPvwbg1wGJiYno7u4mH98B7YmJYQFvK\/Lz88knBT\/c4AHEYuLxdYIP9V9+\/Y1sRewe2NqOR71WS7YlSUo6hDfmzUNKSgpu3LhBgYDPnoUuLti2LRplZWWwt7fHH7m54okH8LY84+AB02LiZWZkkHhdXYP\/5dKSi2QXFVn2dOXE8WPUr0ZzWXgGSTz4LcaNszVsM\/lJy5w5cx97WPCQeOnpaVi3bh0i2CY5Ly+PDgmCgoLYejaYnpjDiePpdPFTW3uN0oaNG4Pg7u4x4pMMc+CpzUtTpsDPz58ufhobG0UNsPKdFXAcco+hSk4mka9dqxMeYwziZanV1DiXRGuCv78\/PNzdMXHiJFmOpjJOHMeECS9SvhQVFQU3V1eWdEeIWstwNDWVfiMfHPyq8eUZMxC9fTvVzZ41C8uXr6DPnMLCAmorNXX1GMRzXbYMTk4PDgQvazT0cHBwiPCYBxePv6+1tZ3sdpZIc3tPrIJsS\/BZSAjGj3+BjcAusr\/av5++A0+CX587B2vWfEh+TnZ2FtXl5PwuPMYYxFsw3xmurm7CAlpY6sGnmTorW3jMQy\/e0CXgPU8POLzyqrDGnuBNm2j069c1vizx76RK+RGrfbyx4M23yM\/5LimJ6q7W\/CM8xgwZeUvh4rJQWMChRCU93Nyso1Bu7nldhlioe3p6hQdwf3flqO5LR0uKanAdq6uvJ7uttZXs8opKJBz4GpMmT2bRlKoQ9nkoXfzzvHQ4DOL9fOoUvaiCbfh1umY4OMzEokWL2aY4HOGsmLvunczMZNFsHI58\/wPtO\/muhPeXnKwSLcYe3u98Z2d89PEnNCB4ouvm9jbVdXZ0YAZLT\/j30TU303qoUqVQ3XAYxOPwCBMYGIjQ0FAolYm41X0LnmzDf\/jwEdFi9JzMzKAps2vXLir85OMntle1NHy0rV37KQWtyMhIdHR0ihqw9KWKRWI\/OkVJTT0qvMPzkHhjiT7PGxzB8t\/KjZSR3FUMh8XE+ybhAOymTRPWswDwL8Ncs29agF7fAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC\"\/>  then what is the value of 9<i>a<\/i> + <i>b<\/i>?\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"207","CORRECT_ANSWER":"207","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu24":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>4<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>3<\/i><i>0<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><b><\/b>The sum of the first 30 terms of an arithmetic progression equals twice the sum of the first 20 terms. Find the ratio of the sum of the first 32 terms to the sum of the first 42 terms of the same progression.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <img Width='15' Height= '30' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAA8AAAAeCAYAAADzXER0AAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAKISURBVEhL3ZXfT1JhGMcRU1OCaNLEZtSCmIty5pXZkuwCMPsLRDNt4QUxanNgV9UMrKQfI0q4odl1Gnbjoiu5wBubF+ZCskEXpG02hhfqUPx2zntednIctrysz\/Zu5\/m+z\/d99zznvO8RoQiRSARWq5WMYPA1tre36QyPoPljOAypVIpWvR5msxkymQy9vX10lkfQfFKjwSndaRoBTzweiEQizM9\/pgqHoPlcczNUx45jfX2DxPfv3SXmePwrifMImn+urECjVkMul0On0xHjqD9AZ3kEzW6Xi9TJ1ut0OqFWn0BHxxVkMhmawVFg\/ra0RHayWm9SBYgvLhJtaOgBVTgKzJ9mZ0nixMQ7qnAoqqvR3n6ZRhwF5uXlHygtFcNgMGJra4to7ycnyYJPnz0ncR7Bmt+MjZFkpVKJpqYm8mwwGrGxwXU\/j6CZJRaLwcU0zuFwIBQKUXU3Rc1\/w79qjkajsNvtsNlsexoDAwMQLSwswOfzwev17mn4\/f7\/otupVAp3BgdhMpnQ2dmJMHMdCTE3NweLpZ83JxIJHKmthUQiQVdXF842NpJv2vvCRzM4YrEvUNbUQCwu5c39lhskOZFIUgW4qG9FleQAstkscrkcPJ4RVFZWory8HHV1R3nzzEwUb8fHacRxva+XLJjb2cGv1VWoVCr4AwE8HHYzi1QVb9j3ZBJlZfvQ3X2VxOzZzp\/vkcePmN0rhM1Jpv7DCgXONDQgs7ZGVR5254qK\/YXmyPQ0DjKXX0vLeaTTaaruRtAcDAZRUlKCnp5rVBGmwPxhaoo0x37rNonZ+thrZ3Nzk8R\/Mux27a5Z33qBvIIGps76+npotVoy2tou0Qye0VcvmR\/CIfwGYqjeY+1IyZQAAAAASUVORK5CYII=\"\/>  \n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <img Width='14' Height= '28' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAA4AAAAbCAYAAABMU775AAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAJQSURBVDhPxZRPSJphHMc9+Af8c03RYa5NIRtsKeku\/js0MHWwHNtOc4fVQA10SaPBgrXRqPCSiFeXuyxhnaq7nZd\/inVLmHUUHQYWmN89Pu9b6l4h2aUPPML39\/p53+eB5\/fj4R9SqXUkk0k2MdRqNawsLyMQCODj4iLq9Tq6xEwmA5lMhtnZCFtheDQ+Dq1Oh2AwCPnAAJ49f9EWX\/l8EIlEkEqlCM7MsFUgtrYGHo+HavUPzdm9n1CpbjFio9HAU68XuVweNqsVL8lLLnHYbXC5PTg8\/IVoNIrtnR1ap2Kz2aShhWlsrEscfXAfSqUScrkcer2efj0UCnefsYXZZOoSddq7EIslyOcLNG9vbVH5WtFoGIXZ\/JBNDJrBwevFgN8PsUSCs\/Nzmkul3+Dz+VxRp9XiyeQkm4DjUgkKhQIjI\/cQiUSgIue12uxcMR6PYyOdZhND8egIPrILi8UCP9lB7fSUK\/bLDYiVSgXFYrHvVS6XGbHVCU6ns+8Vi8UYkf7+Bzcsrq6uQEcaVq1Ww+N5jP2DA\/ZJm3A4RKfAlfj5Ewnk1n9YWCDjI4XbGg3k5KpVq1X6vHlxgXdzc0xbhTvaykvu5+upaTYBuewe\/VM2l6P9ajQYoCEvuzM01LsfL0lvfKfi8ckJnRCJRIIMqTO4JiboB3qK+4UChEIh5uffs5U2djJKpqbfcMXd3QwEAgECwfbA6sThsHPFr+QWtba3tPSFrXDhiJubP6i0nvrGVnrT2mrXGfXDw3Qo2Ww2GI3Gq9UamZ243S6E30bwFwInyZY\/g3jwAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC\"\/>  \n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <img Width='15' Height= '30' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAA8AAAAeCAYAAADzXER0AAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAJ5SURBVEhL1ZXdT1JhHMfBieR46YLZBbJ5FWozoQsbmW42xoVbmUJIV9yQtkWrLu1CVHq7sVUX6bRpsGE5tdyc3SD+A9gN6sBNuVDacHK4AmzDwbfDc5460sElrZs+23N2ft\/n+ez5nbPzIsIJTE9Nwel0khEMBmlaTEnZNTiISokEdrsd1zo6oFKpsLb2lc7yCORodAcikQjPnr+gCVCv1UKnv0QrHoEc29sj8vCImyaAVnsehiuttOIp2fbY2FtI2LYtFgsMBgNqa2sRjkToLI9AzuVyGHK5IJPJYDKZoNfrUVNzDv6VFbqCRyDPzn4kbX\/6vEgTwNbbiyqpFAyTpAmHQH48MEDk43xZXiZZKLROEw6B\/H56miz0+\/k27\/b3kyy+v08TDoGcTqXQdrWVLLbZbsNoNJLzoeERuoJHIBf4fniIl6Oj6OzsZO\/4LSwtLdGZYkrKp+V\/lX0+H7q7u8saHo+Hk6PRKAKBQFlje3ubk8nxL\/n3cjqdJm\/X76TYpy+TydCqhDw+PkbeX4ZhaAIkDg5gNpuhUCigVJ6Fw+FA9uioWJ6cmCDPsaRKikQiQbJsNouLTU0kn19YwIeZGVRUiHHPeZ+Xu25ch1gsxoXGRsjlil87F9q0Wq2Ym5sndYFHDx9AoVRycj6fR19fHzY2N\/Hm9Suyy\/G2j8OwHV1uaUFPj1l4zU+fuE+U77DXWl19BpWVEjJ\/arlw9xfZT5PX64WuuRlt7e3l7fyTjfUQWfNHeXd3l3xNAqurpC7wLRYrLbtHhovkZDJJ6oaGRsTjcVLf7OqCTC4Xyu8mJ6BWq2nFEQmHodPpoNFoUFdXx\/5B6hHZ2sIPKyDj33BF7BYAAAAASUVORK5CYII=\"\/>  \n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Cannot be determined\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"c","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu25":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>4<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>3<\/i><i>0<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><b><\/b>The average of a set comprising the first 2<i>n<\/i> natural numbers is A. If all the odd numbers in the list are doubled and all the even numbers are halved, the average of the 2<i>n<\/i> numbers becomes B. If the difference of A and B is 6, find the sum of the first <i>n<\/i> natural numbers. \n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>210\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>325\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>406\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>496\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"b","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu26":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>4<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>3<\/i><i>0<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>If all the letters of the word SPOON are permuted in all possible ways and the words thus obtained are arranged alphabetically as in a dictionary, then what is the rank of the word OSOPN?\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>34\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>33\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>32\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>35\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"a","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu27":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>4<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>3<\/i><i>0<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><b><\/b>At the start of a party, a basket, placed at the centre of the room, contained 1000 fruits, exactly 99% of which were apples. By the end of the party, the percentage of apples in the basket fell to exactly 98%. If it is known that all the guests ate only apples, how many apples did they eat? \n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>10\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>20\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>50\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>500\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"d","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu28":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>4<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>3<\/i><i>0<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><b><\/b>What is the largest power of 2 in (5! + 6! + 7! + 8!)?\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>3\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>4\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>5\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>None of the above\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"a","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu29":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>4<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>3<\/i><i>0<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>A square well is dug in a rectangular field of length 20 m and breadth 15 m. If the well, when filled to the brim, can hold 7,20,000 litres of water, 10% of which can cover the remaining field upto a height 0.3 m, then the depth, D, of the well, lies in which of the following ranges? (1 m<sup>3<\/sup> = 1000 litres)\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>6 m \u2264 D < 9 m\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>9 m \u2264 D < 12 m\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>12 m \u2264 D < 15 m\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>15 m \u2264 D < 18 m\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"c","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu30":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>4<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>3<\/i><i>0<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><b><\/b>If <i>x<\/i> =  <img Width='33' Height= '31' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACEAAAAfCAYAAABplKSyAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAPxSURBVFhH7ZdbTNNXHMe7UHwQs7pg8PJEuLX1xQUxEdweCNnGw8aDgVC3hciQBCm02OAcjqtLuLmQDccDoIlOpIKt4QmQgELEFzCK3EW6RF5gDLklKEPgu3N+Pf\/\/X9riEkzKkvlJTvr\/nnMevufW8z0qeIGVlRU0NjbCaDTSryteMcH5c2oKKpUKdvttUaPwziZWV1ep\/Bt3WlvJxMyLF6JGwaOJubk59PX14fXrVSwtLWF+fl60uGM2m1FZeUmozfkuORlRUccwMzOD8fFxUevEzcSVy5dhMpnYtNlxwmBAUFAQRkZGRas7CQkJyM8vEMoz6+vrCAkORnh4OAyGRHy0ezeMGRnyDG4wUVpSAr3+IBYWFkl\/8fln2LtvP31vRjIb4cWLPwvlmaGhQVqK78+dw6vlZfx04QJph+MPapdNDA8NwcfHB\/39A6IG0Gm1SDdmCKVQUlyMrKwsKjqdDpGRUbKuqakRvRT44Pz99wgFWOtvkInnExOkZRMJ8fE4ejRSKODhw17q2NnZJWoUBgYG0NvbSyU2NhZpaadlPTY2JnopRBw+jK+\/+VYo4Gx2NkJCQmmZOLKJXX47kZ19lr7\/mp6Gno2Qu59kR+ttJCUlobS0TCh3piYnaTDNzS2kl9lyaDQa2Gx20hzZRDDbgAf2H0BVVRUKCwsRFhoKX98dqKurEz08ExcXh5yc80K509LSTCZGRkcxwaY\/JSUFubl5otWJbGJwcBCpqakoKipiG3MBdpsNeXn5dETfRltbGy3DZvCRt7e3016pra3Fvc5O0aIgm9hO3puQ+G+YcDgcaGhogNVq3ZbS1NQEVU9PD8rKythZL92WUlFR8X5PyPx\/TKytrWFxcRGzs7OYZveSK14xMc+SWnl5ObsQ\/fH7dfe7yGvLce9uhzNDPHdmiDfxmonTaWnQanVCbcSjiQcPulFfX4\/u7m50dXXh8aPHomXr8IxpNmehurqa4gK\/XSXcTGSyAJqRmYnh4WEknzxJU3ifmXkXHOPPoGbRMTo6GhaLBb5qNb78Ko42LGeDCYvlDA4d+lgoIPfH89B8qGGp2NlZgkc4Kc65Fh79XKn89Reo1b4YffqUtNmUSYN7+fIVadlE\/5MncgKSOBIRgcREg1AKPKBIwda1FLMQ7MqnnxzD8ePxQgEmNtP7WIrn7xqObCL1VApLznqhwPbDfTIlZcOtwo8nn36r9aaoAbRhYfghJ0eoN0zodVqK7hw+pTxj+vntIhPS2m2FG3XX2WA+YBvxb9JWtuEDAwPpz0tCNlH12yVKwenp6bh69RoKCwoQEBCAW7dsosfWaG1tQUxMDHvFjaCjo52ejfyZqQD8A6jlTpBAmyAsAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC\"\/>  , <i>y<\/i> =   <img Width='33' Height= '31' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACEAAAAfCAYAAABplKSyAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAOzSURBVFhH7ZdZSFRRGMdHslJbfdJelZQcI8seykJakBanNMOKasxlfKkslcolMNAG1HLEcMmcfHDMvRIFLcMUnMAFc1xABefBwEpUBFPc59+9Z765dnFaqJx68AcH5v99557537PxXQm+4X17OzIzM5GUlIT5+QWKrjwiE1NTU9jpLoVMdooilkFkYn5uDps2bkRu7hOKWAaRibrXr7DG2hrDw8NsVn4F5X0lCgo0pH7O4uIihoaGSBkRmYi8eQMODo6Ijo6Gq6srLl66hMnJScqax++0H+Li4kn9mEKNBrdu3UZZWRnCFeEY0OtZXGTC2dkJLi6u0Ol0qK6qgkQiQV6emrLmCb4SjAcPHpL6Psr7SfDw2M1mWT8wwMaur3\/LcoKJvt5elmjSapkeGxtjWqVKZ9oEP52Pc3KQnJzMmscuD\/j4+Ai6pKSEei6hbWpiY\/X29jE9MjLC\/ocfi0cwkZqagq1b7WEg3dPTzR7UdXZSxIiBe5CfpeLiYta8vLwQGBgo6IaGBuq5xCmZL6RSd1LLEUx47tnN7YHLpIAg+WUcOnSY1PcJkgchJSWVlHlctm9HQMBZUsD09DS02nekyMTszAx7a42mkAVfPH8OT8+93C7+yPSPkPnKEBMTS8o8F86fY+NXVlbizZs6KMIU3H6opyyZWFhYQEV5ObckqVCr1UhPT8fo6Cjr8DPy8\/NRU1NDyjyfP39CWGgovL29cfXqNXR391DGiLAcJmZnZ+mX5Vhm4l+wasKERM9dnaWlpcI5t3TjT4yktbWVO+cpwo1n6aZSqVb3hMD\/Z2KOq6z4+oEvOvj73VKITOg6OuDv7wdHx20YHx+n6MqzbDlOHD8GrwMHSVkGkYkZbglsbWyQp35KEcsgMtHY2AAbzgR\/gSiVStTW1lLm7\/BlYoJVXlVcUdTBLb0JkYnYmDuwsrJCVFQU5HI5qwGKioop+2e0NDdj\/779KC+vQF3da\/ayg4MfWE5kwtnJCSdO+pIC7GxtEXjuPCkjBoMBXV1daGtrM9v6+\/up5xJ8YbvBzg4vuRnmqa6u4g7AGaGSF0zo9cYKuIW7xk3wH0Lx8XdJGVnkCqDExERERkaabdnZOdRziYCAM3Bzk5JajmBClfYQmzdvEYqazk4dM2WqkH8X\/qvOZv16JCTco4iRb4snwYTUbQfkQVdIAUePHMb1iAhSvw9vYt26taKxs7KyRJteMBESEszc8muanZ2FtLQ0yvw5jzIyYG9vjzCFgm36Z8+KKMMDfAX2onWvzIMoagAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==\"\/>  , <i>z<\/i> =   <img Width='32' Height= '28' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACAAAAAcCAYAAAAAwr0iAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAANLSURBVEhL7ZdLLFxRHMZHE9WY0DANSc3aqspKNxbWmGo09WrUzlRbCYlXPBbqMV6JWLGjVUPFq0URjFHEYyUzC1Gj8QjThGSQmXrW13P+c9xWXNrQSBd+yUnm+5+TO9+5\/zN3vqvAGRweHopP8hwcHKCwsBBWq1VU\/o4fR0fik5NTBjo7O1FXV4f29nb09vWJqjwB9wKwtrYm1PkYjUa8qa+HXq9HbU0NKioqqX7CQHT0EyQ+S4TdbkdmRjo8PW+LGXm4geXlZaHOJi01FRqNBjbbJpaXlqBQKPDi5Suakwzk5ebCx8dHKKC7uxtDQwahnGxsbKCxsZFGPduN310\/lJWVSTWLxSJW\/qKl5T08PDyxtbVFemlxkQyMfB4lTQZ4P2+5uUGnK6XiWfB+V1ZW0uBf7Ovri4yMDKlmNpvFSid7e3tQeXujvLxCVIBSnQ5KpRI7OzukycCmzUaujMYRKnKsrLd\/6i9vwerqqlCnGRsdpevOzX0hvch2r1S6Iy7+KWkOGdjd3aGFUVGPsbKygtbWVqSkpLD+rtAiOfgO1H5qmEwmUTnNxw+ddF29vgljY2NISEggHRYWLrVLOgMNDW\/h7++P0NBQZGZmYn19XczIs7+\/j+TkZCyxQ3UWDnaY42JjcT8wEAUFr+kOPAgORlZW9skW\/A6\/8L\/mvGfKKQNXzbUBBf8ZDQ4OYmBg4MqHwWCAYnx8HLnsKZiTk3PlIz8\/\/\/oMXBu4NvAfGnA47JQHe3p6MD8\/L6qXh0c3\/jff19+P2dlZGETaOmFganISISEhaGtrQxtb7OXlxXKcTcxenKYmPcIjIjAxMYHa2hq4uLiwB1EezUkGLJZ5ikpdXd2k3zU0IDLyEcWqY3h04wFkZmZGdsilI+PwMNzd3bGw8JX09PQUhZLjICMZiHyoQWBQkFDybG9vswyYTmlJbnR0dIiVTrh5tVqN0tIyUQGKi4rg7a2SMoJk4KarK4pLdEI5uWw46f3UQ7u1Wr+R\/u5w4I5KhaQkLWmOZOAG64tW+1wooLq6ml4mLkNebg4ZOGJvQ\/zuxcfFkS5hG+WaIxmoKC+nQ6fVapGWlsYOYruYuThms4mie0xMLKqqqtDc3MxiuoplzmyxAvgJW2Of5asIXqEAAAAASUVORK5CYII=\"\/>  , what is the value of <i>x<\/i><i>y<\/i> + <i>y<\/i><i>z<\/i> + <i>z<\/i><i>x<\/i>, given that <i>a<\/i>, <i>b<\/i> and <i>c<\/i> are all distinct two-digit numbers. \n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>-1\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>0\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>1\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>None of the above\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"a","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu31":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>3<\/i><i>1<\/i><i> <\/i><i>a<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>d<\/i><i> <\/i><i>3<\/i><i>2<\/i><i>:<\/i> Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><b><\/b>In a district, there are exactly 15 towns, grouped into five zones, with three towns in each zone. All the possible pairs of towns in the district are now connected with telephone lines, such that any two towns are connected with four direct lines, if they belong to the same zone and with only one direct line, if they belong to different zones. How many direct telephone lines are required in all?\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"150","CORRECT_ANSWER":"150","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu32":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>3<\/i><i>1<\/i><i> <\/i><i>a<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>d<\/i><i> <\/i><i>3<\/i><i>2<\/i><i>:<\/i> Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><b><\/b>There are <i>n<\/i> students in a class, having roll numbers from 1 to <i>n<\/i>. Each student calculated the sum of the roll numbers of all the other students in the class. If the average of the sums calculated by all students is 161.5, then how many students are there in the class? \n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"18","CORRECT_ANSWER":"18","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu33":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><b><\/b><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i> <\/i><i>3<\/i><i>3<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Find the value of <i>k<\/i>, for which the simultaneous equations ( <img Width='29' Height= '28' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAB0AAAAcCAYAAACdz7SqAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAALXSURBVEhLtZY9TFNRGIabQDsBASIDXTCBi4s1kULUqVhwUKiCERQdBYR2IFI16qaYlOKGiANOmLQEN35qtEgoDi0lYnCgAQZISomECClSQQp9Pff0cLGUP+npk3zJfb9zbt5zv\/N3ZfgH39wcDAYDpqenWSY+RJh+sNkgk8kQCPxmmfgQYVpTfReZmUqEQmE9OzuL+fn5sOBIhOkZ1WncvFVFnxsb7+NERgacLhfVPJFMV1b8UMjl6O5+D3OzCampafg6NsZa+SKZupxOJCQkQKvV0nkdH\/\/OWvgjmb5ua6NmKpUKCoUCnZ3vWAt\/JNOKihvIzs7B5uYmrl3VQcg9xVr4w0xDdD6ra2qpsn\/6SL96aMhB9XEJBAJYXl6OCL\/fHzYNbmygrKxMMhF1ZWUFOjreUn1cDHo9kpKSaCQnJ0OpVCIlJWWnvPFgcnISDoeDhotsvZIrl8muSI3dtMtqhd0+wNT+TJEBiFNmH\/gcu2ndvVq0tLxkan\/y1WqcO3+BPsds+vTJ40Pn\/svwMP1Kt3uUapmTHApmsxkmk+nAmJmZoS+I2Gz9aGhooJGXdxYaTaGkxfN6N7rSEghCLlPEdIwcdRaL5dCYI9feNuKz2+2mced2FYzGB5L+tbrKeoVZJToxMRHPnjexDIfyPnpoRHv7G6aiGSUDEUvrICXeJmZTI7mNWltfMRVNl9VCTb3enUrtaRravlCPwMLCDywtLTEVzeLiIjweD4LBIMvsMrWSPSce+IIgoKCgAIODg6yFL5Jpf18fLYO4KIZJ\/a+Xl0MuV2BiwsN68EMybSbborj4ElPAn\/V1Ooimphcsw499F9LIiIua9vb2sQw\/9jRdW1vDyawsaAovYus\/FtVRiTL1+XwQcnKgVufj5wGrMhYiTL+R0yk9PQ2lOh35g9hiWf5Ipl6vl9519fV6lokfkqm+vo4uHG1REf0j1Gg0NHp6elkPXgB\/Acumo4fI4ENNAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC\"\/>  ) <i>x<\/i> + 9<i>y<\/i> = 2 and 3<i>k<\/i><i>x<\/i> + <i>k<\/i><i>y<\/i> = 6 have infinite solutions.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>0\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>40\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>56\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>No such value exists\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"d","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu34":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><b><\/b><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i> <\/i><i>3<\/i><i>4<\/i><i>:<\/i> Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Find number of terms common to the progression 1, 7, 13, 19\u2026.601 and the progression 6, 11, 16, 21\u2026601.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"20","CORRECT_ANSWER":"20","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"}}